Ibragim Zubailov

□+385 68 458679 | ✓ Telegram | @ vulgarnykarlson@gmail.com | to LinkedIn | ♥ Github | ♥ Portfolio | ♥ Bar, Montenegro

SKILLS

Programming: Golang, Typescript, NodeJS, PHP, NestJS, Web3(Blockchain)

Storage: MySQL, Postgres, Clickhouse, Redis, Aerospike

Message brokers: Kafka, RabbitMQ, NATS Transports: REST, WebSockets, GRPC, GraphQL

Others: GlusterFS, ElasticSearch, Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible, Nginx, Prometheus, Grafana

Languages: Russian (native), English (intermediate)

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a Software engineer and leader with a 7 years of experience, with strong fundamentals in NodeJS, Golang, Architecture and Database knowledge.

My expertise in handling high-load systems has provided me with the knowledge to craft optimal application architecture, conduct A/B testing, and transition from monolithic to microservice systems, catering to both business requirements and overall team efficiency.

I've consistently analyzed every aspect of third-party technology implementation, risk assessment, transition phases, and understanding the pros/cons derived from their usage.

WORK EXPERIENCE (6.5 YEARS)

MTS Group Senior Golang and NodeJS Developer

Moscow, Russia

Jun 2022 — Jun 2023

- Develop high-load b2b storage. stack: Golang, NodeJS, Kafka, Clickhouse, RabbitMQ
- Service for optimizing load-balance of storage throughput. stack: golang, glusterfs
- Optimized retrieve data from storage. stack: golang, clickhouse

Lofty Teamlead (8 backend)

Moscow, Russia May 2020 — May 2022

• Developed arbitrage project between advertisers(DSP) and supply platforms (SSP). Actively participated in strategizing business logic development. After 2 years project was generating over 1mil\$ revenue, and having 500k rps. stack: Golang, Aerospike, Kafka, Clickhouse, Postgres, GRPC.

- Processes added to the team: KPI performance review, roadmap planning, mentoring, idea submission point, task decoupling.
- Developed traffic quality evaluation system to predict prices for SSP
- Developed filter system to screen out fraudulent and low-quality traffic.

Techlead (4 backend)

Oct 2019 — May 2020

- Rewrote main application to achieve: stability(no fires), 3x perfomance, A/B Bussiness testing, unit/integration tests, low entry threshold(for newcomers). In 2y growed from 15k to 150k rps.. stack: NodeJS,Clickhouse,Postgres,Redis,Kafka.
- Introduced Agile pipeline, involved in the recruitment process
- Participated in architecture design including devop's and database storage parts.

Senior NodeJS Developer

Jul 2019 — Oct 2019

- Develop high-load (70k rps) push advertisement sender, with a big flexibility of settings. stack: NodeJS, MySQL, RabbitMQ
- Micro-service for authorization

Belsona Investment Group

Moscow, Russia Jun 2017 — Jul 2019

Middle NodeJS Developer

- Develop arbitrage bot between blockchain smart-contract and exchange (Binance/Bitfinex). stack: NodeJS,MySQL,Typescript, Web3(Ethereum), Websockets.
- Design and develop risk evaluation system and a predictive model based on market trends, trading data, blockchain activities.
- Automation scripts for reducing routine tasks, specifically for ICO projects
- Devised service for risk score ICO products.

EDUCATION